<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>In Bartholomew-close, at the signe of the red-ball, with two black posts at the door, near unto Smithfield-gate, lives an expert operator[?]; who, ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B24883</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99889023</idno>
  <idno type="VID">196148</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240902060</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing I1096A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[157]</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99889023</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99889023e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B24883)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 196148)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:2[156])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>In Bartholomew-close, at the signe of the red-ball, with two black posts at the door, near unto Smithfield-gate, lives an expert operator[?]; who, ...</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>With floreated border at head.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Medicine --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine, popular --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Scurvy --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Sexually transmitted diseases --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-04 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>Anne Simpson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="advert_for_quack_medicine">
            <pb facs="tcp:196148:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>In</hi> Bartholomew-Close, <hi>at the Signe of the</hi> Red-Ball, <hi>with Two</hi> Black Posts <hi>at the Door, near unto</hi> Smithfield-gate, <hi>lives an Expert</hi> Operator; <hi>who,</hi>
            </head>
            <p>BY the Blessing of God, in his many years Travels, and large Experience in Forreign Countries, hath attained to many Rare Secrets in Physick, by which he hath per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed wonderful Cures on many hundreds of Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple: There never was more Pretenders to Cure the <hi>POX,</hi> than there is now: But Friends, have a care how you fall into the hands of such Ignorant preten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders; for if they once but get you into their Clutches, they will use you as unmerciful, as they are unskilful. Therefore be not ashamed to seek help in time; come to me; for the Disease is soon Cured by him that hath the right way (if you use him); for he is not one that cures a Clap by chance, or keeps you Physicking Months together.</p>
            <p>He Cureth the <hi>Gonorrhaea,</hi> or <hi>Running of the Reins,</hi> i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> newly contracted, in a Week or Ten Days; but if Rebellious or Virulent <hi>Sores,</hi> Stinking <hi>Matter, Sharp Pains,</hi> or <hi>Heat</hi> and <hi>Stoppage of Ʋrine,</hi> he Cures in Twenty Days at Farthest: <hi>Hemorrhoids, Ragged Chaps,</hi> and <hi>Clefts</hi> in the <hi>Fundament,</hi> Pockey <hi>Swellings,</hi> and <hi>Buboes in the Groin, pains in the</hi> Back, <hi>with Nodes, Knots,</hi> or <hi>Exostices</hi> on the <hi>Head,</hi> and <hi>Shin-bones;</hi> al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>so <hi>Scabs, Itch, Pusles, Tettars, Ring-worms,</hi> or Break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings out of the whole Body: All which he can Cure without Fluxing or Sallivating, although never so bad, as many by good Experience can well testifie, that in three Weeks or a Month at farthest, have been restored by his <hi>Never failling Pills;</hi> which are so faithfully prepared; that the tenderest Pati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent
<pb facs="tcp:196148:2"/>may take them, and go about their business, without loss of time, or cause of suspition to their nearest Relation, or danger of Relapse. He likewise Cures the <hi>Stone in the Riens,</hi> or <hi>Bladder,</hi> with much ease. This <hi>Pill</hi> is the true <hi>Antidote,</hi> against the <hi>Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy;</hi> The <hi>Scurvy</hi> is the cause so many Diseases are long growing, and steal upon People, then prove hard to Cure; such lurking Diseases, few are sensi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble at first, but now and then taking a Dose of these <hi>Pills;</hi> might prevent their coming, and procure Health: for that Medicine which will Cure the <hi>Scur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy;</hi> will reach any Disease. A Dose or two of these <hi>Pills</hi> commonly Cures any small <hi>Clap,</hi> and keeps the Party from being Infected by the Disease.</p>
            <p>These <hi>Pills,</hi> the best and cheapest of all Physick, are three Shillings a Box, and 18 Pence a Box, Seal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed up with Printed Directions how to use them; they are excellent good for Seamen to take to Sea with them; for they keep their full Vertue for Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven Years.</p>
            <p>He Cures the <hi>Griping of the Guts,</hi> although never so violent, in half an hours time; and gives present ease in the <hi>Tooth-ach,</hi> in the greatest extremity of pain.</p>
            <p>He hath likewise a <hi>Stone,</hi> which makes black or yellow <hi>Teeth</hi> as white as Ivory, in half an hours time; a safe <hi>Powder</hi> that brings away all sorts of Worms at once, in Children or others, and clears the Body to admiration; a <hi>Water</hi> which takes all <hi>Kedness, Pimples,</hi> or <hi>Scabs</hi> out of the <hi>Face,</hi> in two or three Days time, and leaves the Skin <hi>smooth and clean. He Cures Agues of all sorts.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A Private Lodging may be had if Desired.</hi> And his House is so private, that no notice can be taken of your coming to him; And he will freely give his advice for nothing.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Ae is to be</hi> spoken <hi>with from</hi> 6 <hi>in the Morning, till</hi> 12, <hi>and from</hi> 2 <hi>till</hi> 10 <hi>at Night.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>